JEFF MCKEAN FRONTEND DEVELOPER & MULTIMEDIA SPECIALIST

BACKGROUND

With a foundation in the Visual Arts, I have a comprehensive understanding of the fundamentals of composition and design and apply principles from these disciplines towards digital content creation. I have years of experience working with all forms of media including drawing, painting, animation, photography, film, and video and utilize my experience from these artforms as part of the process of translating ideas into visually compelling content. I recognize pixel-level shifts in detail, maintain a consistent and accurate representation of any design and layout, and find creative solutions to manage complex design requirements.

MARKETING

My experience working for smaller marketing agencies as the principal frontend web developer and multimedia specialist has given me the opportunity to work on a diverse range of responsibilities related to digital marketing communications. From coding custom designed registration sites connected to cloud database systems, constructing and deploying responsive HTML Email Ad campaigns, conceptualizing animations for web and social media platforms, video post-production editing, effects, and compression, Google Cloud Platform integration, along with managing hosting, domains, DNS, and accounts for third party services connected with our company and client sites.

Additionally, I employ an array of resources towards page-load performance, Accessibility, and SEO, and understand the importance of testing and staying connected with current web development technologies.

I have years of experience collaborating with clients in the real-estate development, engineering, and mining and exploration industries, which includes simplifying technical considerations and problem-solving unique specifications that come with almost every project.

For work examples and more, please visit imckean44.netlify.com

LANGUAGES & TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML
- CSS/SASS (Flexbox & CSS Grid)
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- PHP
- CMS (WordPress, Wix)
- Astro JS SSG & SSR
- Radix UI/React Hook Forms
- NPM/Node.js
- GitHub/GitHub Actions
- Visual Studio Code
- SFTP/SSH

HOSTING & DNS

- WHM/cPanel admin, web and email hosting
- Netlify
- Resend
- DNS/Nameserver management and troubleshooting

ACCESSIBILITY & SEO

- ARIA labelling
- WAVE Accessibility Testing
- Cumulative Layout Shift prevention
- Site structure, naming conventions, metatags, descriptive keywords, alt tags, image optimization

SOFTWARE

Proficient with Mac and PC

- Adobe Creative Cloud:
- Adobe Animate
- Premiere Pro

Photoshop

- After Effects
- Illustrator
- InDesign

Handbrake Video Transcoder

Microsoft 365 Suite

Trello

TESTING TOOLS & PERFORMANCE

- BrowserStack
- Litmus
- Lighthouse/DevTools/PageSpeed Insights
- Privacy Sandbox Analysis Tool (PSAT)
- Google Tag Assistant
- Meta Pixel Helper

WORK EXPERIENCE

P&B Marketing Ltd.

Frontend Web Development & Multimedia 2013 to Present

P&B Marketing provides marketing services to clients in the real-estate development industry. At P&B, I have been responsible for:

Websites & CMS

- Managing between 8 12 client websites in-house
- · Multi-tasking between numerous client projects and deadlines
- Converting custom designs from Adobe Illustrator and InDesign into responsive, cross-browser/devicetested registration sites built in PHP and Astro JS SSG/SSR framework
- Content Management Systems (WordPress, Wix, Joomla)
 - Creating custom themes and templates
 - o Maintenance and content updates
 - o Ensuring backups are in place and working
 - o Troubleshooting WP Core and PHP/plugin version conflicts
- Webform integration with cloud database systems like MailChimp, Zoho Creator, and Onyx Technologies
- GSAP parallax scrolling
 - o ScrollTrigger
 - o ScrollSmoother
 - SplitText
- Image colour correction, art direction, and optimization with modern webp/avif formats and jpg/png fallbacks
- Page composition and transitions
- Custom UI and UI Framework integrations
 - o Accordions
 - o Tabbed content
 - o Image banner carousels
 - o Lightbox, Modal/popup windows, Tooltips
- DOM manipulation
- Customized Google Maps
- Responsive developer floorplans with information UI, including customizing Mapplic floor plans component

Email Campaigns

- MailChimp API and Zoho Creator lead management and integrated email campaigns
- · Hand-coded HTML emails with optional two and three column stackable layouts
- Outlook conditional comments for maintaining an accurate design

- Tested in Litmus
- Deployed through MailChimp
- Post campaign performance metrics

Hosting & DNS Admin

- WHM server management, security, web and email hosting set up
- · DNS and Nameserver configuration and troubleshooting
- Manage company and client domains, web and email hosted accounts
- SSL certificates

Animation & Video

- · Client video editing and modifications
 - o Masking, looping, optimizing, easing
 - o Export and optimization for web
- · Vector/bitmap banner Ad animations for web and social media
- · Responsive landing page animations and videos with desktop and mobile versions

Accessibility & SEO

- ARIA attribute states, labelling, roles, and accessibility compliance
- Google PageSpeed Insights/Chrome Lighthouse performance checks and best practices
- SEO reviews, descriptive metatags, keywords, page titles, and image alt tags
- Sitemaps
- Organized site structure and naming conventions

Third Party Services

- · Google Cloud Platform
 - o Accounts & billing admin
 - o Google Analytics setup, installation, and reporting
 - $\circ \quad \text{Google Tag Manager setup, installation, and integration with Facebook Meta Pixel} \\$
 - o Cloud Run
 - o App Engine
 - o reCAPTCHA
- Microsoft 365 admin & troubleshooting
- Zapier
- Cookie consent setup, integration, and customization
- · MailChimp company and client account management and API integration
- Troubleshooting company and client hosting-related issues, including managing a blacklisting and dedicated server move during a transitional phase as one of my first responsibilities

Pectopah Productions Inc.

Frontend Page Templates and Layouts April - August 2013 (Contract) ific.ca

Financial Investment company website redesign

- Converted PSD comps using Adobe Photoshop and Fireworks into graphics for the landing and interior pages
- Built the HTML pages with the Zurb Foundation framework
- Implemented a Flexbox layout to accommodate a client decision regarding how to manage long button names
 in multiple languages. The Flexbox option allowed each top-level navigation link to wrap within its own
 unordered list until a certain break point before switching to a mobile layout
- Created custom media queries for fine-tuning animated transitions between breakpoints
- Prepared and formatted a responsive CSS/SASS/jQuery dropdown mega-menu
- Using conditional comments to detect Internet Explorer versions 8 and 9, I created custom style sheets to properly position page elements where IE failed to recognize CSS markup
- Semantic HTML practices
- Validated pages using the W3C Markup Validation Service
- Used Firebug browser developer tool for page inspection and editing
- @font-face typography

Exploration Link Ltd.

Web Design / Construction / Content Management 2000 - 2012

As the lead web designer at Exploration Link, I was responsible for designing and developing mostly investor relations websites for a variety of successful businesses in the mining and exploration, engineering, and software development industries, as well as a successful jewellery design company. I enjoyed positive and friendly long-term client relationships as a result of consistently delivering creative solutions and meeting time-sensitive deadlines in a collaborative time-billing environment.

- Over ten years of experience designing and constructing corporate brochure websites with custom functionality, including Flash animation, jQuery UI, and image carousels using Adobe Creative Suite 5 and Microsoft Expression Web
- Familiar with ASP.NET Master Pages for managing centralized page templates
- Coordinated with clients through the design and build stages
- Used diplomacy and expedited workarounds and solutions to technical problems and rush jobs
- Managed multiple projects and daily content updates
- Designed and prepared company branding for print, trade show banners, and our company website
- Edited, converted, and embedded client videos using Adobe Premiere and Flash player

- Using Adobe Flash Professional, I created custom animated vector-image project maps and bitmap-image banner animations
- Logo design
- Responsible for maintaining branding consistency between company stationary, print materials and the website

<u>Kinross Gold</u>, <u>PDAC</u>, Riva Modelling, and <u>Anne Sportun Jewellery</u> are example sites we managed branding, website and print design.

Images Film & Video

Video Production / Post-Production 1994 – 2000 imageslifemedia.com

- Editor
- Videographer

EDUCATION

Ryerson University	Film, Video, Multimedia (B.A.)	1995 - 2000
OCAD	Fine Arts and Graphic Design	1987 - 1989
Sheridan College	Fine Arts and Graphic Design	1986 - 1987